<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! I am Subash. on Subash Parajuli</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi! I am Subash. on Subash Parajuli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember). I want you to be able to work from your own laptop in this workshop, but Cloud is an important back-up plan should you run into troubles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;#34;postcards&amp;#34;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS). packageVersion(&amp;#34;postcards&amp;#34;) [1] ‘0.2.0’ Create GitHub repo Online.
Clone GitHub repo usethis::create_from_github(&amp;#34;https://github.com/apreshill/global-postcard.git&amp;#34;) ✨ Commit &amp;amp; Push! ✨</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;#34;blogdoown&amp;#34;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS). packageVersion(&amp;#34;blogdown&amp;#34;) [1] ‘1.0’ Create GitHub repo Online.
Clone GitHub repo usethis::create_from_github(&amp;#34;https://github.com/apreshill/global-blogdown.git&amp;#34;) ✨ Commit &amp;amp; Push! ✨</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS). &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’ Create GitHub repo Online.
Clone GitHub repo usethis::create_from_github(&amp;quot;https://github.com/apreshill/global-distill.git&amp;quot;) ✨ Commit &amp;amp; Push!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description> Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection My layout is: single-series part 2! does this work? now for some very cool things more get ready! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Methods using R</title>
      <link>/project/quantr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/quantr/</guid>
      <description>Quantitative Methods using R This book covers practical worked out examples which you can easily apply to your data set and also includes a discussion on how the example is working. We will cover descriptive and basic inferential statistics, including graphs, frequency distributions, central tendency, dispersion, probability, hypothesis testing, tests of mean differences, correlation, simple regression, and chi-square tests. This book is designed to facilitate graduate students of Educational Psychology to develop their knowledge and understanding of various statistical concepts and procedures in R programming as a supplement resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instructional Technology</title>
      <link>/project/canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/canvas/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few support resources and materials I developed during my tenure as an Instructional Technology Trainer.
A short tutorial to create triggers in Qualtrics - A short screencast of Canvas Orientation Course for Faculty </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Blockchain in Education</title>
      <link>/blog/blog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/blog-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Blockchain technology has been making waves in various industries, and education is no exception. As the world becomes more interconnected and data-driven, the need for secure, transparent, and efficient systems in education is more crucial than ever. In this blog post, we will explore how blockchain can revolutionize the education sector by enhancing security, improving record-keeping, and fostering innovative learning experiences.
Secure and Immutable Record-Keeping One of the most promising applications of blockchain in education is the creation of secure and tamper-proof digital records for students and institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Analytics and the Power of Teacher Dashboards</title>
      <link>/blog/color-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/color-themes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
The advent of digital technologies and data-driven decision making has significantly impacted the education sector. One such innovation is teaching analytics, which involves collecting, analyzing, and interpreting data to enhance teaching and learning experiences. A teacher dashboard is a vital component of teaching analytics, providing educators with an accessible and user-friendly interface for monitoring student performance, engagement, and other essential metrics. In this article, we will explore the concept of teaching analytics and the benefits of using teacher dashboards to support data-informed decision making in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A campfire</title>
      <link>/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>/talk/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power BI and Data</title>
      <link>/project/powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/powerbi/</guid>
      <description>Few of the dashboards and analytics tools we worked on to inform the ITSM and technology trends in R1 universities. What problem are you trying to solve using technology ? Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss.
Portfolio ITSM Dashboard Template Visit App
This app was designed as a part to continuously monitor the KPI metrics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webfolio</title>
      <link>/project/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/websites/</guid>
      <description>Affordable web design and web app services to emerging businesses and professionals to help them reach their audience. Below are a few of the websites I&amp;rsquo;ve designed. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for web design services, please feel free to contact me for a free quote. What problem are you trying to solve using technology ? Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss.
Portfolio Egyanship.com Visit Website
An online learning company.
Innovativepalia Visit Website
A teacher training company run in Nepal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Literacy Projects</title>
      <link>/project/vizlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/vizlit/</guid>
      <description>A short documentary on &amp;ldquo;Deficit Ideology&amp;rdquo;
Presentation on Color Wheel
An instructional video on parallel parking</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes A A A A A A A A 6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px) Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>/about/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/skills/</guid>
      <description>::: {.panel} ::: {.panel-heading} Instructional Design ::: ::: {.panel-body}
ADDIE Storyboarding eLearning SCORM Gamification UDL ::: ::: ::: {.panel} ::: {.panel-heading} Data Analysis &amp;amp; Visualization ::: ::: {.panel-body}
R SQL SPSS Stata Tableau ::: ::: &amp;hellip; (add more panels as needed)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
